Be free or die
Harriet is a drama, history film directed by Kasi Lemmons.
The extraordinary tale of Harriet Tubman's escape from slavery and
transformation into one of America's greatest heroes.
Her courage, ingenuity and tenacity freed hundreds of
slaves and changed the course of history.
Harriet Tubman, played by Cynthia Erivo.
William Still, played by Leslie Odom Jr..
Marie Buchanon, played by Janelle Monáe.
Ben Ross, played by Clarke Peters.
Rit Ross, played by Vanessa Bell Calloway.
Bigger Long, played by Omar J. Dorsey.
Harriet is a 2019 American biographical film directed by Kasi Lemmons,
who also wrote the screenplay with Gregory Allen Howard.
It stars Cynthia Erivo as abolitionist Harriet Tubman, with Leslie Odom
Jr., Joe Alwyn, and Janelle Monáe in supporting roles.
The film received several accolades and nominations, particularly for Erivo's performance, which
garnered her nominations at the Academy Awards, Golden Globes, and the Screen Actors Guild.
For the song "Stand Up", Erivo and Joshuah Brian Campbell
received Oscar, Grammy and Golden Globe nominations.
The film explores themes of southern usa, slavery,
biography, harriet tubman, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.